Guide to the Larry Spruch Papers MC.209
New York University Archives
- Series V: Research, 1949-2004
  - Subseries B: Drafts and Unpublished Writings, 1964-2004
    - "Pedagogical notes on classical Casimir effects," Larry Spruch, 2004 (Box 31, Folder 23)
    - Wave function graph transparency, undated (Box 31, Folder 24)
    - Appendix A of article written with Leonard Rosenberg, undated (Box 31, Folder 25)
    - "A useful variational principle for the scattering length for the target ground-state wave function imprecisely known," R. Blau, L. Rosenberg, and L. Spruch, undated (Box 31, Folder 26)
    - "Atoms in the Intense Magnetic Field of a Neutron Star", undated (Box 31, Folder 27)
    - "Pedagogic notes on some ramifications of Thomas-Fermi theory", undated (Box 31, Folder 28)
    - "A slightly different derivation of the leading corrections to the Thomas-Fermi density for the r not near the origin", undated (Box 31, Folder 29)
    - "Remarks on the existence and accuracy of the z-1/3 expansion of the nonrelativistic ground-state energy of a neutral atom" and "Truncated expansion of the ground-state energy of a neutral atom in powers of z-1/3: cofficients of the leading terms," Robin Shakeshaft and Larry Spruch, undated (Box 31, Folder 30)
    - "Exchange currents, magnetic moments, and isomeric transitions," Larry Spruch, undated (Box 31, Folder 31)
    - Corrected fragments of untitled manuscript, undated (Box 31, Folder 32)
    - References from Spruch's Science article, undated (Box 31, Folder 33)
    - Articles for Larry Spruch website, undated (Box 31, Folder 34)
    - Analycity paper draft, undated (Box 31, Folder 35)
    - "A Note on Nuclear Radiative Capture Cross-Sections and the Solar Neutrino Problem", undated (Box 31, Folder 36)
    - "A generalized Levison theorem: applications to electron-atom scattering," and "Absolute determination of zero-energy phase shifts for multiparticle single-channel scattering: a generalized Levinson theorem," Leonard Rosenberg and Larry Spruch, undated (Box 31, Folder 37)
    - "The Casimir interaction of a plasma with confining ideal parallel metallic plates," Martin Schaden and Larry Spruch, undated (Box 31, Folder 38)
    - "Variational Principles, Subsidiary Extremum Principles, and Variational Bounds," Larry Spruch, undated (Box 31, Folder 39)
    - "A Summary of Dirac Notation for Finite Dimensional Space", undated (Box 31, Folder 40)
    - "Rearrangement Collisions at Very High Energies," Robin Shakeshaft and Larry Spruch, undated (Box 31, Folder 41)
    - "Constructing variational principles," E. Gerjuoy, A. R. P. Rau, and Larry Spruch, undated (Box 31, Folder 42)
    - "New Stationary Bounds on Matrix Elements, with Application to Positron-Atom Scattering," Robert Blau, Leonard Rosenberg, and Larry Spruch, undated (Box 31, Folder 43)
    - Russian manuscript, undated (Box 31, Folder 44)
    - Comments on L. Wilets' abstract on replacing Uncertainty and Pauli principles with a potential, undated (Box 31, Folder 45)
    - "A unified treatment of some Casimir energies and Lamb shifts: a dielectric between two ideal conductors," Martin Schaden, Larry Spruch, and Fei Zhou, undated (Box 31, Folder 46)
    - "Semiclassical Evaluation of Some Casimir Effects," M. Schaden and L. Spruch, undated (Box 31, Folder 47)
    - "The Moment method in relativistic radiative transfer," J. L. Anderson, E. A. Spiegel, and Larry Spruch, undated (Box 31, Folder 48)
    - "Charge transfer at high impact velocities," Robin Shakeshaft and Larry Spruch (galleys), undated (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Subseries C: Notes and Calculations, 1949-2004
    - Notes on Electromagnetic Theory course taught by Julian Schwinger at Harvard, 1949 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Résumé of articles on magnetic moments, 1951 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Notes on time reversibility, 1952 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - References and notes on mesons, 1952 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Notes on M. Gell-Mann and M. L. Goldberger, "The Formal Theory of Scattering", 1953 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Notes on various aspects of scattering theory, 1956, 1959 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Notes on the existence of bound states, 1959 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Deduction using coupled equations and Green's Functions, 1959-1964 (Box 41, Folder 13)
    - Notes on p-d scattering (by Spruch and Kalman Kalikstein), 1960-1961 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Notes for Yugoslavia, 1962 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Notes on conversations with other physicists, 1963-1966 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Notes on variational principles for break-up, 1964-1970 (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Spruch's notes on Shakeshaft's manuscript on charge exchange, 1964-1975 (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Notes on necessary conditions for the existence of bound states, 1965 (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - Notes on necessary conditions for bound states, from Yugoslavia meeting, 1965 (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - Calculations of the probability of correctly filling in one square of a crossword puzzle, 1966 (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - Notes on Green's function for fourth order differential equations, 1966 (Box 32, Folder 16)
    - Notes on long-range forces, 1966 (Box 32, Folder 17)
    - Notes on bounds on cross sections (including adiabatic), 1967 (Box 32, Folder 18)
    - Notes on cosmology: magnetic moment, 1967-1969 (Box 32, Folder 19)
    - Notes on bound states, 1968 (Box 32, Folder 20)
    - Notes on R. Haag, "Quantum Theory of Collision Processes", 1968 (Box 32, Folder 21)
    - Notes on multi-channel scattering, in R. G. Newton's Scattering Theory of Waves and Particles, 1968 (Box 32, Folder 22)
    - Notes on some properties of U (t, t0), 1968 (Box 32, Folder 23)
    - Notes on long-range effects, 1969 (Box 32, Folder 24)
    - Notes on Bondi: relativity and common sense, 1970 (Box 32, Folder 25)
    - Notes on variational principles for break-up, with Mike Lieber, 1970-1974 (Box 32, Folder 26)
    - Notes for "Adiabatic Approximation and the Other (Lower) Bound on the Scattering Length," Yukap Hahn and Larry Spruch, 1971 (Box 32, Folder 27)
    - Spruch's notes on the "Constructing Variational Principles" manuscript by Gerjuoy, Rau, and Spruch, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 28)
    - Notes for "Adiabatic Approximation and the Other (Lower) Bound on the Scattering Length," Yukap Hahn and Larry Spruch, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 29)
    - Notes on the Low soft photon theorem, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 30)
    - Notes on the soft photon theorem in the presence of a Coulomb potential, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 31)
    - Notes on various topics, 1973-1981 (Box 32, Folder 32)
    - Calculations by Spruch and A. R. P. Rau for "Simple Model Wave Function for Atoms in Intense Magnetic Fields", 1974 (Box 32, Folder 33)
    - Notes on variational bounds on A, via adiabatic approximation, 1974 (Box 32, Folder 34)
    - Spruch's and Edward Gerjuoy's notes on systematic construction of variational bounds, 1974 (Box 32, Folder 35)
    - Notes on various topics, 1974-1991 (Box 32, Folder 36)
    - Notes for article on hydrogen atoms in intense magnetic fields, written with A. R. P. Rau, 1975 (Box 32, Folder 37)
    - "Energy levels of hydrogen in magnetic fields," A. R. P. Rau and Larry Spruch (notes), 1975-1976 (Box 32, Folder 38)
    - Notes on bound states, 1976 (Box 32, Folder 39)
    - Notes on Girshgorin's Theorem applied to bounds on a scattering length A, 1977 (Box 32, Folder 40)
    - Notes on improved variational principles, 1977 (Box 32, Folder 41)
    - Notes on Lamb shifts, 1977 (Box 32, Folder 42)
    - R-5: Some details of the calculation, 1977 (Box 32, Folder 43)
    - Notes: normalization of hydrogenic momentum space wave function, 1977 (Box 32, Folder 44)
    - Notes: asymptotic evaluation of capture to bound states (classical), 1977-1978 (Box 32, Folder 45)
    - Improved evaluation of MTT, 1977, 1985 (Box 32, Folder 46)
    - Notes on various topics, 1978 (Box 32, Folder 47)
    - Notes on a conversation with John Kohl, 1978 (Box 32, Folder 48)
    - Notes on Sciana, thermodynamics of black holes, 1978 (Box 32, Folder 49)
    - Derivation of variational principle for A, 1978 (Box 32, Folder 50)
    - Notes on calculating variational bounds on energy, using model potential approach, 1978 (Box 32, Folder 51)
    - Possible problems to study, 1978-1983 (Box 32, Folder 52)
    - Notes on the interaction of an electron and a conducting wall, 1978 (Box 32, Folder 53)
    - Notes on various topics, 1978-1988 (Box 32, Folder 54)
    - Notes on calculating the self-energy of an electron bound to a perfectly conducting wall, 1979 (Box 32, Folder 55)
    - Notes on self-energy of electrons, 1979 (Box 32, Folder 56)
    - Notes for high K manuscript, 1979 (Box 32, Folder 57)
    - Notes on Modified Effective Range Theory and functions with poles, by Larry Spruch, Leonard Rosenberg, and Edward Novak, 1980 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Notes on Schwinger, "Thomas-Fermi Model: the leading correction", 1980 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Notes on the Scott (Coulomb) model, 1980 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Notes on Thomas-Fermi theory, 1980 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Notes on E. Teller, "On the stability of molecules in the Thomas-Fermi theory", 1980 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Notes on the statistical theory of Bosons, 1980 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - "Odds and Ends" on N 5/3 for Bosons, 1980 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Notes on Dyson and Bosons, 1980 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Notes on Leontieff, 1980 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Notes on ionization energy, the Scott model, pion condensation, Thomas-Fermi theory, Bosons, Holder's Inequality, and convexity, 1980-1981 (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Notes on the definition of the continuous function N(Z) of the continuous variable Z, and the Scott model, 1980-1981 (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - Notes on L'Hôpital's Rule and Coulomb corrections to white dwarf model, 1981 (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - Variational principle for a gamma function, 1981 (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - Notes on nucleosynthesis, 1981 (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - Notes on polarizability in Thomas-Fermi theory, 1981 (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - Notes on conversations with other physicists re: He+ ions, 1981 (Box 33, Folder 16)
    - Notes on other physicists' papers on nucleosynthesis, 1981-1982 (Box 33, Folder 17)
    - Spruch's notes on "Bounds in heat conduction" by Kalman Kalikstein and Alberto Baider, 1981-1982 (Box 33, Folder 18)
    - Notes on retarded (Casimir) potentials, 1981-1982 (Box 33, Folder 19)
    - Notes on correspondence with Robin Shakeshaft, 1981-1984 (Box 33, Folder 20)
    - Notes on polarizability of neutrons, 1981-1988 (Box 33, Folder 21)
    - Notes on potential scattering, 1982 (Box 33, Folder 22)
    - Notes on analyticity, 1982 (Box 33, Folder 23)
    - Notes on phase shifts, harmonic oscillator approximation, and 3He + 4He, 1982 (Box 33, Folder 24)
    - Notes by Birek on radiative capture at low energies, 1982 (Box 33, Folder 25)
    - Notes and calculations re: J-51 tax law, 1982-1983 (Box 33, Folder 26)
    - Notes and calculations on analytic effective-range function in the presence of both repulsive Coulomb and short-range potentials, and on the solar neutrino problem, 1983 (Box 33, Folder 27)
    - Notes on a conversation with Piet Hutt, 1983 (Box 33, Folder 28)
    - Notes on quantum correction to Newtonian gravity, 1983 (Box 33, Folder 29)
    - Notes on Levinson's Theorem and repulsive Coulomb potentials, 1984 (Box 33, Folder 30)
    - Notes on phase shifts and Levinson's theorem, 1984 (Box 33, Folder 31)
    - Notes for "Photoexcitation and photoejection of an electron image-bound to a wall," Larry Spruch and Robin Shakeshaft, 1984 (Box 33, Folder 32)
    - Notes on magnetic monopoles and quantum fluctuation, 1985 (Box 33, Folder 33)
    - Notes on variational bounds on the energy, scattering length, and scattering parameters for the one-body Dirac equation, 1985 (Box 33, Folder 34)
    - Notes on Physical Review Letters article by Au, Feinberg, and Sucher, 1985 (Box 33, Folder 35)
    - Notes on R-5, 1985 (Box 33, Folder 36)
    - α(ω) material, 1985 (Box 33, Folder 37)
    - Notes on various topics, 1985 (Box 33, Folder 38)
    - Notes on work by Mohanty, 1986 (Box 33, Folder 39)
    - Notes: "Helium-like Rydberg atom", 1987-1988 (Box 33, Folder 40)
    - Notes: "p to s", 1988 (Box 33, Folder 41)
    - Notes by Spruch and W. Johnson on a beta-decay manuscript, 1988, undated (Box 33, Folder 42)
    - Notes on various topics, 1989-1996 (Box 33, Folder 42)
    - Notes and clippings on various topics, 1989-2002 (Box 33, Folder 43)
    - Notes for manuscript on semiclassical approach to electromagnetism, 1990 (Box 33, Folder 44)
    - Proof of bound state in two dimensions (from conversation with Alan Sokol), 1990 (Box 33, Folder 45)
    - References and notes on Thomas Fermi theory, 1990 (Box 33, Folder 46)
    - Notes on Lifshitz's treatment of Casimir effects, 1990-1992 (Box 33, Folder 47)
    - Connections between Casimir interactions, 1990, 1994 (Box 33, Folder 48)
    - Notes on various topics, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 49)
    - Derivation of Veeτ, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 50)
    - Notes on the Casimir effect, 1991-1993 (Box 33, Folder 51)
    - Notes on V. L. Ginzburg, "Applications of electrodynamics in theoretical physics and astrophysics", 1992 (Box 33, Folder 52)
    - Notes for biography, 1993 (Box 33, Folder 53)
    - Notes on Wall and Fei, 1994 (Box 33, Folder 54)
    - Notes on Casimir interactions, 1994-1995 (Box 33, Folder 55)
    - Notes on the generalized Levinson theorem, 1995 (Box 33, Folder 56)
    - Notes on the Levinson theorem, 1995-1996 (Box 33, Folder 57)
    - Notes on Levinson theorem manuscript, 1995-1996 (Box 33, Folder 58)
    - Notes on plasma walls, 1995-1997 (Box 33, Folder 59)
    - Notes on polarizabilities, 1996 (Box 33, Folder 60)
    - Notes on articles by Friedrichs, 1996 (Box 33, Folder 61)
    - Notes and correspondence re: "Near-Degeneracy Effect on Polarization Energy Shift in Some Highly-Charged Few-Electron Rydberg Ions", 1996 (Box 33, Folder 62)
    - Notes: seminar on "Near-Degeneracy Effect on Polarization Energy Shift in Some Highly-Charged Few-Electron Rydberg Ions" by Frischat, Schüßler, Spruch, and Wolf, 1996 (Box 33, Folder 63)
    - Notes on Thomas-Fermi theory, 1996 (Box 33, Folder 64)
    - Notes on semi-classical quantization, 1996 (Box 33, Folder 65)
    - Notes on Casimir and Lamb, 1997 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Notes on pion-nucleon scattering, 1998 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Calculations: massless scalar field, 2000 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Notes on Feynman path integrals, 2000 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Notes and comments on semiclassical physics, 2000 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Notes on temperature-dependent Casimir effects, 2004 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Notes on Schwinger, long-range potentials, undated (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Notes on Schwinger, second correction to the Thomas-Fermi model, undated (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Notes on the bounds of the Dirac Equation, undated (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Exact Solutions of Dirac Equation, undated (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Notes on Heitler, Scattering of Dirac Particle by Coulomb Field, undated (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Relativistic corrections to ρ (Z), undated (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Notes on angular momentum in a two-electron system, undated (Box 34, Folder 13)
    - Notes on various topics, undated (Box 34, Folder 14)
    - Notes on second quantization of a radiation field, undated (Box 34, Folder 15)
    - Notes on upper and lower bounds in variational methods, undated (Box 34, Folder 16)
    - Notes on the existence of bound states, undated (Box 34, Folder 17)
    - Notes on bound states: Green's functions and trace technique, undated (Box 34, Folder 18)
    - Notes for "Adiabatic approximation and variational lower bounds on binding energies and phase shifts", undated (Box 34, Folder 19)
    - Notes on recent activities, undated (Box 34, Folder 20)
    - Notes on Green's Functions, undated (Box 34, Folder 21)
    - Notes on various topics, undated (Box 34, Folder 22)
    - Notes on the Low theorem, undated (Box 34, Folder 23)
    - Calculations on existence of bound state symmetric to proton in hydrogen atom, undated (Box 34, Folder 24)
    - Notes on Appendix A of Edwin Lassettre, "Momentum eigenfunction in the complex momentum plane", undated (Box 34, Folder 25)
    - Notes on internal bremsstrahlung, undated (Box 34, Folder 26)
    - Notes on Walter Kohn, "On the Convergence of Born Expansions", undated (Box 34, Folder 27)
    - Notes on Walter Kohn, "Variational Methods in Nuclear Collision Problems", undated (Box 34, Folder 28)
    - Notes on Weinberg, multi-particle bound states, undated (Box 34, Folder 29)
    - Notes on bound states: majorization, undated (Box 34, Folder 30)
    - Notes on minimum principles, undated (Box 34, Folder 31)
    - Notes for "Simple heuristic derivation of the charge transfer", undated (Box 34, Folder 32)
    - Notes on Richard Feynman: disentangling, undated (Box 34, Folder 33)
    - Notes on bounds related to Kato formalism, undated (Box 34, Folder 34)
    - Notes on non-invasive bomb detection, undated (Box 34, Folder 35)
    - Notes on gravitational radiation, undated (Box 34, Folder 36)
    - Notes on one-dimensional systems and genetic code in Asimov, undated (Box 34, Folder 37)
    - Notes on Weinberg: bound states and multiparticles, undated (Box 34, Folder 38)
    - Notes on cosmology and astrophysics, Born and probability; news clippings, undated (Box 34, Folder 39)
    - Notes on various topics, undated (Box 34, Folder 40)
    - Notes on bounds on continuum functions, undated (Box 34, Folder 41)
    - Notes on Dyson, undated (Box 34, Folder 42)
    - Notes on general relativity and black holes, undated (Box 34, Folder 43)
    - Notes on scattering theory, undated (Box 34, Folder 44)
    - Notes on Massimo, inflation, undated (Box 34, Folder 45)
    - Notes on Kaplansky and H. L. Mencken, undated (Box 34, Folder 46)
    - Notes on economics, undated (Box 34, Folder 47)
    - Notes for puzzles, undated (Box 34, Folder 48)
    - Astrophysics calculations, undated (Box 34, Folder 49)
    - Notes on scattering by center of force, undated (Box 34, Folder 50)
    - Calculations: Coulomb potential, undated (Box 34, Folder 51)
    - Notes on the Casimir effect (transparencies), undated (Box 34, Folder 52)
    - Notes on Dyson: bosons, undated (Box 34, Folder 53)
    - Simple derivation of classical Coulomb scattering, undated (Box 34, Folder 54)
    - Notes on the many body problem, undated (Box 34, Folder 55)
    - Notes on the Bohr Model, undated (Box 34, Folder 56)
    - Calculations re: corrections to Thomas-Fermi theory, undated (Box 34, Folder 57)
    - Notes on pulsar molecules, undated (Box 34, Folder 58)
    - Notes on chapter X of Blatt and Weisskopf, Theoretical Nuclear Physics, undated (Box 34, Folder 59)
    - Notes on scattering of polarized particles, undated (Box 34, Folder 60)
    - Calculations of H--'s ability to support a bound state, undated (Box 34, Folder 61)
    - Notes on the stability of matter, undated (Box 34, Folder 62)
    - Notes on Lieb and Thirring, undated (Box 34, Folder 63)
    - Calculations, undated (Box 34, Folder 64)
    - Notes on construction of tensors, undated (Box 34, Folder 65)
    - Notes on E. R. Harrison, "The Early Universe," Physics Today, June 1968, undated (Box 34, Folder 66)
    - Notes on Gold and Watson's Time Deposit Wave research, undated (Box 34, Folder 67)
    - Notes on Gerjuoy and Rau, simple variational principle, undated (Box 34, Folder 68)
    - Notes on Bohr-Pauli, undated (Box 34, Folder 69)
    - Notes on lectures given at Port Washington, L. I., undated (Box 34, Folder 70)
    - Notes on internal conversion, undated (Box 34, Folder 71)
    - Notes on interaction of magnetic moments, undated (Box 34, Folder 72)
    - Calculations: integrand with branch points, undated (Box 34, Folder 73)
    - Notes on properties of light nuclei, undated (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Notes on various topics, undated (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Notes on Steve Winter, "Low energy Bremsstrahlung in low energy scattering and the Low theorem", undated (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - "Odds and Ends" on Casimir interactions, undated (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Various calculations, undated (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Various calculations, undated (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Notes: analyticity of wave function, undated (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Notes on probability, undated (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Notes on long-range interactions (transparencies), undated (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Notes on a manuscript with Robin Shakeshaft, undated (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Notes on publication of chapter 1 in Long-Range Casimir Forces, undated (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Notes on phase shifts, undated (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - Subseries D: Research Proposals and Contracts, 1951-2003
    - U.S. government research contract proposals, 1951-1979 (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Army Research Office proposals, 1969-1970 (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - NSF University Science Development Supplementary Grant proposal, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 15)
    - NSF Supplementary Grant Final Report, 1974 (Box 35, Folder 16)
    - "Theoretical Atomic Physics and Scattering Theory, and Astrophysics," L. Rosenberg and L. Spruch (NSF Supplementary Development Grant Final Report), 1974 (Box 35, Folder 17)
    - Travel forms and contract amounts, 1974-1979 (Box 35, Folder 18)
    - Office of Naval Research proposals, 1976-1980 (Box 35, Folder 19)
    - NSF grant proposal, Leonard Rosenberg and Larry Spruch, 1979-1983 (Box 35, Folder 20)
    - Referees' reports for Rosenberg and Spruch NSF grant proposal, 1979-1983 (Box 35, Folder 21)
    - Office of Naval Research contract renewal, Leonard Rosenberg and Larry Spruch, 1983-1985 (Box 35, Folder 22)
    - Contract matters, 1985 (Box 35, Folder 23)
    - Office of Naval Research contract extension, 1985-1986 (Box 35, Folder 24)
    - NSF grant, Larry Spruch and Leonard Rosenberg, 1986-1994 (Box 35, Folder 25)
    - Edward Gerjuoy supplement to NSF grant, 1989-1990 (Box 35, Folder 26)
    - NSF grant materials, 1989-1990 (Box 35, Folder 27)
    - NSF proposal, 1990 (Box 35, Folder 28)
    - NSF proposals and renewals, 1990-1992 (Box 35, Folder 29)
    - NSF proposal, budget, notes, 1994 (Box 35, Folder 30)
    - NSF budget, 1994-2000 (Box 35, Folder 31)
    - NSF proposal, 1999 (Box 35, Folder 32)
    - NSF proposal, 2002 (Box 35, Folder 33)
    - NSF grant renewal proposal, "Theoretical Investigation of Atomic Structure and Scattering Processes", 2003 (Box 35, Folder 34)
    - "The semiclassical approximation applied to Casimir effects," M. Schaden and L. Spruch research proposal, undated (Box 35, Folder 35)
    - U.S. Atomic Energy Commission security clearance forms (blank), undated (Box 35, Folder 36)
- Series VI: University of Pennsylvania Coursework, 1943-1950
  Series VI contains Larry Spruch's coursework from the University of Pennsylvania, where he was enrolled as a Ph.D. student in physics from 1943 to 1948. Many of the materials in this series are quite fragile and should be handled with care.
  - Physics 161: Electricity and Magnetism, 1943 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Physics 515: Acoustics, 1944 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Physics 620: Electromagnetic Waves, 1944 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Physics 610: Electronics, 1944 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Physics 500: Theory of Functions, 1944 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Electricity and Magnetism problems, 1944 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Mixed coursework, 1944-1945 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - University of Pennsylvania exam forms, 1947-1950 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Physics 630: Quantum Mechanics, 1945 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Physics 630 quiz, 1945 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Physics 600, 1945 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Physics 513: Electronic Physics, 1945 (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Physics 511: Thermodynamics, 1945 (Box 36, Folder 13)